Bojin Zhou



In College I was particularly strong in Maths and Physics and wanted to use those strengths to learn something practical and useful, so I chose to do a computer science degree. After I graduated, I continually looked for a career in IT. I had training in .NET and later I became an IT consultant, working in various companies and organization including East Sussex County Council and Barclays bank. I like the brain challenge of solving a problem and I am interested in using technologies to improve people's lives. Outside work I like learning Buddhism and I practice different types of meditation: walking meditation, chanting and being mindful in whatever things I do. I like to explore people's inner world and actively seek meaning in life. I like reading Chinese traditional cultural classics to find wisdom to use in my life.

SUMMARY

I attained a degree in Computer Science from King's College London, a Masters degree in Buddhist Studies from SOAS, and I am currently training with futureproof. In my previous role I worked as a .NET developer delivering application development and support using C# object-orientated language and Microsoft technologies. I was responsible for improving the functionality of systems in close consultation with the business and end-users.

I have experience working as an Admin in a recruitment agency, as an IT consultant specialising in .NET technology and as a .NET web developer working in a fast-paced leading website company maintaining their backend systems.

I am now looking forward to finding a role to use the skills recently acquired in my futureproof training.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Futureproof | Tech Trainee | Jan 2022 - Present

GitHub: https://github.com/bojin11 and http://github.com/bojin511

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Databases, and Python.
- Recently completed a group project using JavaScript to create a simple search engine web API, using Jest to

Oscore | C# developer | Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

- Worked in a .NET house as a contracted C# developer, being involved with various projects such as using C# Xamarin to develop a mobile solution. Used .NET windows forms to improve a real-time trading application. Gained experience building unit tests using NUnit.

Betway | .NET web developer | Sep 2014 - Dec 2014

- Worked in a leading website company as a .NET developer, gaining development skills in .NET Umbraco, MVC, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, C#

FDM Group | .NET IT Consultant | Feb 2012 - Sep 2014

- Worked in East Sussex County Council and Barclays to develop and manage .NET solutions

EDUCATION

SOAS University | Sep 2019 - July 2021 | MA Buddhist Studies (PASS)

King's College London | Sep 2006 - July 2010 | BSc Computer Science (2:2)

Tower Hamlets Sixth Form College | Sep 2004 - July 2006

A-levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (B), Further Mathematics (C), Economics (C)

TECHNICAL SKILLS